brothers and sisters to another
Wednesday question and answer where we
open up with the ten commandments that
God had written for the whole world to
keep. Tenzel,
>> and God spake all these words, saying, I
am the Lord thy God, which have brought
thee out of the land of Egypt, out of
the house of bondage. Thou shall have no
other gods before me. Thou shalt not
make unto thee any graven image, or any
likeness of anything that is in heaven
above, or that is in the earth beneath,
or that is in the water under the earth.
Thou shall not bow down thyself to them,
nor serve them. Why the Lord thy God am
a jealous God, visiting the iniquities
of the fathers upon the children, unto
the third and fourth generation of them
that hate me, and showing mercy unto
thousands of them that love me, and keep
my commandments. Thou shall not take the
name of the Lord thy God in vain. For
the Lord will not hold him guiltless,
that take of his name in vain. Remember
the Sabbath day to keep it holy. Six day
shall thou labor do all thy work. But
the seventh day is the Sabbath of the
Lord thy God. And in it thou shall not
do any work. Thou nor thy son, nor thy
daughter, thy man's servant, nor thy
maid servant, nor thy cattle, nor thy
stranger that is within thy gates. For
in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, the sea, and all that in them is,
and rested the seventh day. Wherefore
the Lord blessed the Sabbath day, and
hallowed it. Honor thy father and thy
mother, that thy days may be long upon
the land which the Lord thy God giveth
thee. Thou shall not kill. Thou shall
not commit adultery. Thou shall not
steal. Thou not bear false witness
against thy neighbor. Thou shall not
cover thy neighbor's house. Thou shall
not cover thy neighbor's wife, nor his
man's servant, nor his maid servant, nor
his ox, nor his ass, nor anything that
is thy neighbors. We read Exodus 21-17.
And may the Lord have a blessing to the
reading of his word. In Jesus name we
pray. Amen.
>> Amen.
So here on question and answer, you can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the vague as well as
the long scripture questions and
questions of debate. We are not here to
debate. We are here to spread the true
gospel of Jesus. So, please be as direct
as possible with your questions so we
can be as direct as possible with our
answers out of the King James Bible. No
other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. Also, keep
in mind that this is a live stream, so
feel free to send in your questions that
pertain to everlasting life. We just
asking that you keep your questions to a
two scripture maximum. Let me introduce
you to you the family that's on the
panel this evening. Brother Jerome,
>> rest in peace.
>> Brother Julius.
>> All right, you're on mute, but we
>> Good evening everybody.
>> Brother Jerome,
I got you. Brother Dre,
>> good evening.
>> Brother Tanzel,
>> Sister Deborah,
>> good evening. Brother Sean,
>> good evening.
>> And we have the guest caller with us and
I'm brother Cornell. Sister Deborah,
what is our first question of the
program?
>> Yes. Uh there are several heldover
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A. Kenya
B. Haynes has two questions. She asks in
Job 1:es
6-11,
who in the Godhead was Satan dealing
with and do angels deal directly with
the father or do they deal only with
Jesus like man?
>> All right. So they want to knowing that
Job 16-11, who is the godhead and who
was Satan dealing with? So let's go
there. Brother Tanzel, the Job 1 and
verse 6, and a guest caller take it from
there.
>> Now there was a day when the sons of God
came to present themselves before the
Lord. And Satan came also among them?
And the Lord said unto Satan, "Whence
comest thou?" Then Satan answered the
Lord and said, "From going to and fro in
the earth, and from walking up and down
in it?" And the Lord said unto Satan,
"Hast thou considered my servant Job,
that there is none like him in the
earth, a perfect and an upright man, one
that fear God, and is true as evil?" And
then Satan answered the Lord and said,
"Doeth Job fear God, for no hast not
thou made a hedge about him, and about
his house, and about all that he have on
every side? Thou hast blessed the work
of his hands, and his suffering is
increasing the land. But put forth thy
hand now, and touch all that he have,
and he will curse thee to thy face.
>> Okay.
>> All right. Guess caller.
>> Well, the thing is is Jesus.
He's the one that calls it all. Even
when the Lord uh uh uh
wanted to use an ang when when the angel
did something, let's look at the
protocol. Who who who is the one that
directed the angels? Let's go into
Revelation the first chapter and read
verse one.
>> Revelation
the revelation of Jesus Christ
which God gave unto him
to show unto his servants things which
must shortly come to pass and he sent
and signified it by his angels unto his
servant John.
>> So now that's the protocol father deal
with Jesus and Jesus sent the message to
man but by who? By his angel because
Jesus is the one that control the
angels. Jesus is the one that
communicate. The father only talks with
Jesus. Go to Revelation 22:16.
Revelation 22 and 16.
>> I Jesus have sent my angel to testify
unto you these things in the churches. I
am the root and the offspring of David
and the bright and morning star.
So now I Jesus sent my angel to testify
these things. Jesus is the one that deal
with them holy or unholy. Now we going
to show you when the father will come
into the picture. Let's go to 1
Corinthians the 15th chapter.
Read verse 22 to 26
verse.
For as in Adam all die, and even so in
Christ shall all be made alive. But
every man in his own order, Christ the
first fruit, and afterward they that are
Christ at his coming.
Then cometh the end, when he shall have
delivered up the kingdom to God, even
the Father, when he shall have put down
all rule and all authority and power,
for he must reign till he have put all
enemies under his feet. The last enemy
that shall be destroyed is death.
>> Uhhuh.
Now skip down to verse 28.
>> When all things shall be subdued unto
him, then shall the son also himself be
subject unto him that put all things
unto him, that God may be all in all.
>> Okay. So now Jesus got to put everything
down, even Satan. Let's go into
Revelation 7th chapter
and we're going to start where he said
and and and and Satan was cast into the
lake of fire and then we got the white
throne judgment.
>> You said Revelation um is that
>> I'm sorry the 20th chapter of
Revelation. I'm sorry. Right.
>> And we going and we going to start at
verse five. We're going to read until
Satan is uh uh uh uh
is loosed. Go ahead.
>> But the rest of the dead live not again
until the thousand years were finished.
This is the first resurrection. Blessed
and holy is he that have part in the
first resurrection. on such the second
death have no power, but they shall be
priests of God and of Christ, and shall
reign with him a thousand years. And
when the thousand
[Music]
years are expired, Satan shall be loose
out of his prison.
>> Now see, the Lord had put Satan in
prison for a thousand years that he
going to be on earth. That Jesus going
to be on earth. Now when the thousand
years over he going to loose Satan out
of his prison and Satan going to go and
deceive the whole world and they going
to surround the camp of the saints. Then
star and fire came down uh uh uh uh uh
from heaven and devoured them.
>> And they went up on the breath of the
earth and compassed the camp of the
saints about and the beloved city and
fire came down from God out of heaven
and devoured them.
>> And the devil that deceived them was
cast into the lake of fire and brimstone
where the beasts and the false prophet
are. And they should be tormented day
and night forever and ever.
>> And I saw a great white throne, and him
that sat on it, from whose face of the
earth and the heaven fled away, and
there was found no place for them. And I
saw the dead, small and great, stand
before God. And the books were open, and
another book was open, which is the book
of life. The dead were judged out of
those things which were written in the
books according to their works.
Go ahead.
>> And the sea gave up the dead which were
in it. And death and hell delivered up
the dead which were in them. And they
were judged every man according to their
works. And death and hell were cast into
the lake of fire. This is the second
death. And whosoever was not found,
>> finish it.
>> And whosoever was not found written in
the book of life was cast into the lake
of fire.
>> Okay. So now when Jesus came
to do his thousand year rule, he had
Satan at another angel lock Satan up.
Then after the thousand years, he lose
Satan and Satan deceive the world. a lot
of people they tried to attack the camp
of the saints. Fire came down from God
and kill the army. Then Satan was cast
into the lake of fire
and then they had white throne judgment
and everybody that was uh uh uh going to
make it made it and everybody that was
not going to make it was cast into the
lake of fire. And Jesus also terminated
death.
All that was done by Jesus. So once all
that was done, then when did the father
come into the picture?
Revelation
21 and 1.
And I saw a new heaven and a new earth.
For the first heaven was and the first
earth were passed away, and there was no
more sea. And I, John, saw the holy
city, New Jerusalem, coming down from
God out of heaven,
>> prepared as a bride adorned for her
husband.
>> Now, skip down to verse four and read
it.
>> And God shall wipe away all tears from
their eyes, and there shall be no more
death, neither sorrow, nor crying,
neither shall there be any more pain,
for the former things are passed away.
Mhm.
>> And he that sat upon the throne said,
"Behold, I make all things new." And he
said unto me, "Right, for these words
are true and faithful."
And he said unto me, "It is done. I am
Alpha and Omega, the beginning and the
end. Now we give unto him that is a
thirst of the fountain of the water of
life freely."
Right. We back up to show where God, it
said he going to dwell among men. That's
the father now.
>> Uh verse three.
>> Read it.
>> And I heard a great voice out of heaven
saying, "Behold, the tabernacle of God
is with men, and he will dwell with
them, and they shall be his people, and
God himself shall be with them and be
their God."
And after that there was no more death.
So now Jesus is dealt with deals with
the angel. Jesus had Satan locked up by
another angel. And when Jesus had him
loose for a thousand years and Jesus put
him in the lake of fire. Then Jesus rule
had the white throne journey. Jesus
terminated death. And once all that was
done, everybody that's supposed to be in
the lake of fire was in it. Then that
21st chapter brings the father's
kingdom. So now that was Jesus dealing
with Satan in Job the sixth chapter that
first chapter
and Jesus only have dealt with man and
angels. The father don't even come into
the picture until Jesus turned the
kingdom over to him. And when did he do
that? The 21st chapter of Revelation.
That's all I got to say.
All right, I hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next
question.
>> Moving on. Sky Ryder says if Christ's
death terminated animal sacrifices
then why is there sacrifices in the
future kingdom according to Isaiah 56
6 and 7 and Isaiah 66 20- 23.
>> All right. So if Christ death terminated
the animal sacrifice during that time
then why is it that there'll be
sacrifices in the future? Brother
Jerome, what you got?
>> Let's go read the verses um given in the
question. Isaiah 56
verse 6 and 7.
also the sons of the stranger that join
themselves to the Lord to serve him and
to love the name of the Lord to be his
servants everyone that keepeth the
Sabbath from polluting it and take up
hold of my covenant. Even then will I
bring to my holy mountain and make them
joyful in my house of prayer and their
burnt offerings and their sacrifices
shall be accepted upon my altar. For my
house shall be called a house of prayer
for all people.
in Isaiah 66 verse 20- 23.
And they shall bring all your brethren
for an offering unto the Lord out of all
nations, upon horses, and in chariots,
and in litters, and upon mules, and upon
swift beasts, to my holy mountain,
Jerusalem, said the Lord, as the
children of Israel bring an offering,
and a clean vessel into the house of the
Lord.
Okay. So, uh
you read that 23, right?
>> Oh, no. Keep on going all the way. 23.
>> Yeah.
>> And I will also take of them priests and
for Levites, said the Lord. As for the
new heavens and the new earth will I
make
shall remain before me, said the Lord.
So shall your seed and your name remain.
And this shall come to pass that from
one new moon to another, and from one
Sabbath to another, shall all flesh come
to worship before me, sayeth the Lord.
>> Okay.
Now, we we understand um at the Israeli
God that um you know, sacrifices,
the sacrificing of animals, we
understand that they don't take away
sin. Okay? But we we know that animal
sacrifice is going to be reinstituted,
but they not being reinstituted
to take away sin cuz the blood of
animals can't take away sin. So they
being reinstituted for another reason.
Okay. So, let's go to
let's go to uh go ahead, guest car,
>> go ahead and finish your I got something
to say.
>> Okay.
Uh
let's go to that uh numbers 18
and we're going to read verse 8 through
11 and we going to skip to 19.
number 18
8-11.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
And the Lord spake unto Aaron, Behold, I
have also have given thee the charge of
my heath offering of all the hollow
things of the children of Israel. Unto
thee have I given them by reason of the
anointing, and to thy sons by ordinance
forever.
And this shall be thine of the most holy
things, reserve from the fire every
oblation of theirs, every meat offering
of theirs, and every sin offering of
theirs, and every trespassing offering
of theirs, which they shall render unto
me, shall be most holy for thee, and for
thy sons.
>> Mhm.
>> And the most holy place shall thou eat
it. Every male shall eat it. It shall be
holy unto thee. Mhm.
>> And this is dying the heap offering of
their gift with all the wave offerings
of the children of Israel. See all these
offerings he's he's giving he's giving
it to them because there was there was a
time where uh
the Levites and Levitical priests they
they they had to go out in the field and
and and take you know regular jobs and
stuff because you know Israel wasn't
doing what they were supposed to do as
far as bringing the offerings. All
right. And these offerings the Lord was
using
uh not only at that time to take away
sin and things like that, but he was
using the the the the meat and the
things like that that was being offered
for the uh the priests for to eat and
for for their family, you know.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, so they he he's portions of
these offerings are being eaten by the
by the priests and the Levites. Okay.
But Israel wasn't doing their job and
bringing these offerings. So Levi and
them had to go out in the field and take
regular jobs. Well, that ain't what the
Lord wanted. So he had made a a a
covenant with them. And he said, you
know, I'm going to make this covenant
with you all. And it's actually called a
covenant of salt. Okay. So um go ahead
and finish that 11. We going to skip to
verse uh 19.
I have given them unto thee, and to thy
sons, and to thy daughters with thee by
a statue forever. Everyone that is clean
in thy house shall eat of it.
>> Okay, skip down to verse uh 19, read to
the 20.
>> All the heave offerings of the holy
thing, which the children of Israel
offer unto the Lord, have I given thee,
and thy sons and thy daughters with
thee, thy statue forever. It is a
covenant of salt forever before the Lord
unto thee and to thy seed with thee.
>> Yeah.
In order for the Lord to keep this
covenant of promise with them, he had to
reinstitute animal sacrifices, you know,
and so that they can have these portions
of sacrifices that he was going to give
to the the uh the priests and the
Levites
uh of the Levit of the Levitical
priesthood, you know, for their sons and
their daughters. All right? So, he had
to reinstitute the animal sacrifice in
order to do that. Okay. Now I wanted to
also um add Did you Did you finish that
20?
>> Yeah, we at 20 now.
>> Go ahead.
>> And the Lord spake unto Aaron, thou
shalt have no inheritance in their land.
He just shall thou have any part among
them. I am thy part and thy inheritance
among the children of Israel.
>> Yeah. And so the offerings that were
supposed to be given were were made unto
the Lord. The Lord turned around and
gave those to the priests in order to do
what we've been reading as far as the
eating of those sacrif portions of those
sacrifices for them and their daughters
and their sons. Okay. Now, I wanted to
tie this with Ezekiel.
Let's go to Ezekiel 44 cuz now we
talking about the second coming of the
Lord. And he going to be in this in this
temple. He going to have a a a court, a
inner court and an outer court. And the
people going to be bringing the
offerings,
>> right?
>> Okay.
So, go to Ezekiel uh 44
and read verse
10 and 11.
We going to skip after that.
Go ahead.
>> And the Levites that are gone away far
from me, when Israel went astray, which
went astray away from me after their
idols, they shall even bear their
iniquities.
Yet there shall be ministers in my
sanctuary, having charged at the gates
of the house, and ministering to the
house. They shall slay the burnt
offerings and the sacrifice for the
people, and they shall stand before them
to minister unto them.
>> Mhm. Skip down and read verse 13- 16.
And they shall not come near unto me to
do the office of a priest unto me, nor
to come near to any of my holy things in
the most holy place, but they shall bear
their shame in their abominations which
they have committed. But I will make
them keepers of the charge of the house,
for all the servants thereof, and for
all that shall be done therein.
>> Verse 15.
>> Yeah.
But the priests, the Levites, the sons
of Zadok, that kept the child in my
sanctuary, when the children of Israel
went astray from me, they shall come
near to me to minister unto me, and they
shall stand before me to offer unto me
the fat and the blood, said the Lord
God.
>> Verse 16,
>> they shall enter into my sanctuary, and
they shall come near to my table to
minister unto me, and they shall keep my
charge.
>> All right, this is the second. This is
after the second coming of the Lord. All
right. When they be in Jerusalem. Okay.
Skip down and read verse 27 through30.
>> And in the and in the day that he goeth
into the sanctuary unto the inner court
to minister in the sanctuary, he shall
offer a sin offering, said the Lord God.
>> And it shall be unto them for
inheritance. I am their inheritance. And
he shall give them no possession in
Israel. I am their possession. Mhm.
>> They shall eat the meat offering and the
sin offering.
>> See, they shall eat they shall eat the
meat offering and the sin offering
because he gave it to them as a covenant
of salt in that numbers. Go ahead and
finish.
>> And the trespass offering and every
dedicated thing in Israel shall be
theirs.
>> What else? Go ahead. And in the first of
all, the first fruit of all things, and
every oblation of all, of every sort of
your oblation shall be the priest. You
shall also give unto the priest the
first of your adult, and he may cause
the blessing to rest in thy house.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And um that that's all I got
on that, you know.
>> All right. Guest caller, would you like
to chime in?
>> Yeah. So anybody paid the fl paid
attention to the flavor of this
question?
>> Okay, read it again.
>> The question is if Christ death
terminated animal sacrifices
then why is there sacrifices in the
future kingdom?
>> Okay, the thing is that if Christ death
terminated
animal sacrifice, let's establish that
first. Go to Daniel 9 and we're going to
start reading at verse 25 through 27.
All right. Daniel 9
and we're going to pick it up in verse
25.
So know therefore and understand that
from the going forth of the commandment
to restore and to build Jerusalem unto
the Messiah, the prince shall be seven
weeks and three score in two weeks, and
the streets shall be built again, and
the walls even in trouble time.
>> And after three score and two weeks
shall Messiah be cut off, but not for
himself.
And the people of the prince that shall
come shall destroy the city and the
sanctuary. And the end thereof shall be
with the flood. And until the end of the
war desolations are determined.
And he shall confirm the covenant with
many for one week. And in the midst of
the week, he shall cause the sacrifice
and the oblations to cease. And for the
over
Jesus Messiah. So he going to come and
he going to confirm the covenant with
many for one week and in the midst of
the week he going to call the sacrifices
in the old blessing the cease.
>> That's when he died on the cross. That's
why when he died on the cross the veil
of the temple ripped where they went and
made the blood of the sacrifice. But now
let's go into Hebrews the 10th chapter.
And we want to establish one thing for
sure
and that is
he terminated animal sacrifice. No ifs.
That is an absolute fact.
>> 10 and one.
>> For the shadow, I mean for the law,
happiness shadow of good things to come
and not the very image of the things can
never with those sacrifices which they
offer yearbyear continually make the
comeras there unto perfect.
>> So now they couldn't make the comeras
there too perfect. So and why is that?
Skip down to verse four and and go and
read four and find
go.
>> For it is not
for it is not possible that the blood of
bulls and of goats should take away
sins.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Wherefore when he come into the world he
said sacrifice and offerings thou
wouldest not but a body has thou
prepared me?
>> Now there's a body. So what do they need
with that body? Skip down to verse 10
and read it.
By the which will we are sanctified
through the offering of the body of
Jesus Christ once for all. Agreed.
>> And every priest of daily ministering
offerings often times the same sacrifice
which can never take away sins.
>> Go ahead.
>> But this man after he had offered one
sacrifice for sins forever sat down on
the right hand of God.
from henceforth expecting shall his
enemies be made his foottool.
>> Go ahead.
>> For by one offering he hath perfected
forever them that are sanctified.
>> Agree.
>> Well, the Holy Ghost also is a witness
to us. For after that he had said
before, this is the covenant that I will
make with them after those days, sayeth
the Lord. I will put my laws into their
hearts, and in their minds will I write
them. In their sins and iniquities will
I remember no more.
Now, where remission of these is, there
is no more offering for sin.
>> That's an absolute, isn't that correct?
>> Right.
>> Skip down to verse 26 and read it. For
if we sin willfully after that we have
received the knowledge of the truth
there remainth no more sacrifice for
sins but a certain fearful looking out
>> that that's point blank isn't that
correct
>> the years old that mean that the Lord
terminated no not if he uh uh sacrifice
was terminated he terminated absolutely
now why he's going to rein reinstate it
when he got get got back the brother
made a plausible
uh uh presentation, but I give a shorter
answer than that because he God and he
can start anything he wanted once he get
back.
>> Praise the Lord.
>> That is right.
>> All right.
>> Yes, call.
>> We hope that answered your question as
we continue to move on to our next one.
>> Next one. Be alert as is it okay to get
baptized in the name of Yesua?
And can you get baptized any day besides
the Sabbath?
>> All right, first question. Is it okay to
get baptized in the name of Yeshua? Not
at the Israel of God. At the Israel of
God. Um, we speak English. The Bible we
read not of the King James Bible is
written in English and we are also
taught in English. So no, not at the
Israel of God. But can you um get
baptized any day other than the Sabbath?
Sure you can.
Sure you can. Let's go into Acts 2 and
let's see what Peter uh said here
because this is in English, too.
And let's see what Peter said. Let's
pick it up at Acts 2 and 38.
Acts 2 and 38.
Go ahead.
>> Uh pick it up. Pick it up at that 36.
Let's just read down into it so we can
get the the English version of the name
we talking about here who you had to get
baptized in. Go ahead, brother.
>> Therefore, let all the house of Israel
know assuredly that God have made that
same Jesus whom you have crucified both
Lord and Christ.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Now when they had heard this, they were
pricricked in their heart. And they said
unto Peter and to the rest of the
apostles, "Men and brethren, what shall
we do?"
>> What did Peter say?
>> Then Peter said unto them, "Repent and
be baptized, every one of you, in the
name of Jesus Christ for the remission
of sins, and ye shall receive the gift
of the Holy Ghost."
>> So we baptize in the name of Jesus, the
one who came and died for the sins of
the whole world. And read that verse 41.
Then they that gladly received his word
were baptized. And the same day there
were added unto them about 3,000 souls.
>> So then they that gladly received his
word. See, we speak English. So we
needed to receive this word here in
English,
>> right?
>> And because we reading out of a book
that's English, and because we taught
English and hey, we baptized in the name
of Jesus, the anointed one who came to
die for the sins of the whole world. And
yeah, you can get baptized a day other
than the Sabbath day. And that's all I
got. If anybody else want to add.
>> Yeah, I want to add something.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Let's go and see what the Lord said by
the prophet Malachi.
>> All right,
>> let's go to Malachi one and we going to
read verse six and then we're going to
skip
>> Malachi 1 and6.
Mhm.
>> A son honorth his father and a servant
his master. If then I be a father, where
is my honor? And if I be a master, where
is my fear?
>> Now he's asking who is he said talking
to? Go ahead.
>> Say the Lord of hosts. Unto you, oh
priest that despise my name.
>> Who is the priest?
>> Israel.
>> That's right. unto you, oh priest, that
despise my name.
>> So let me So now he telling you how to
find out what name he's talking about.
Skip down to verse 11
and read it.
>> For from the rising of the sun,
even until the going down are the same,
my name shall be great among the
Gentiles.
>> Wait a minute. Who are the Gentiles?
white people. Yeah,
>> that's right. The son of Jat. All white
folks.
My name shall be great among the
Gentile. So what is the greatest name
among the Gentiles?
>> Jesus.
>> Point blank. Keep reading.
>> And in every place incense shall be
offered unto my name, and a pure
offering.
For my name shall be great among the
heathen, sayeth the Lord of hosts.
The heathen mean nations,
>> right?
>> That covers all of it.
>> Yeah.
>> How many nations
you hear talking about Yosua or Yahashua
or what's the other name they call it?
>> Yakqua, Yehuda,
>> stuff like that.
>> Even you don't hear that from from a
handful of Hebrew Israelites. But
according to the prophet Malachi, the
prophet Malachi to whom God spoke to, he
said his name is going to be great among
the Gentiles
and among the heathen. The greatest name
among the nations
and the Gentiles is Jesus. Israel got a
problem here. Let's go in here Malachi
two and start at verse one. This is a
message to you, my brother, Hebrew
Israelite. This is directly to you. Read
it.
>> And now, oh ye priests, this commandment
is for you.
>> If you would not hear and if you would
not lay it to heart,
>> hold on, brother. He ain't talking to
nobody else but Israel. This is and this
is what they're saying.
>> This message is to you, oh my priest.
But we are the priest of God. Go ahead.
to give glory unto my name, sayeth the
Lord of hosts.
>> Verse two,
>> if you will not hear, if you will not
lay it to heart
to give glory unto my name, said the
Lord of hosts, I will even send a curse
upon you, and I will curse your
blessing.
>> Yeah, I have cursed him already because
he do not lay it to heart. That's when
you won't give it to my lame. I didn't
curse you. I'm I'mma bring a grace curse
upon you. I done curse you already
because you won't live it to heart.
What? To give glory unto his name.
So the name
that the Lord calling
say it's going to be great among the
Gentiles. He He didn't say a name. He
said my name, didn't he?
>> Amen.
>> Yeah.
and also is going to be great among the
nations. What name is greater among the
nations?
>> Jesus.
>> Therefore, he said in Acts, the name of
Jesus is the only name given under the
son where my men might be saved.
>> There is no other name.
So I suggest wherever you get baptized
at the Israel of God or anywhere else.
If you don't get baptized in the name of
Jesus,
you didn't get baptiz baptiz baptized in
the name that the Lord said going to be
great among the Gentiles and great among
the nation which is Jesus. That's all I
got to say.
>> All right. Thank you for that add-on.
Hope that answered your question as we
continue to move on.
>> Moving on. Etica Masala asked, "What did
Simeon mean
when he told Mary, "A sword shall pierce
through thy own soul when reading Luke 2
34 and 35."
>> Brother Dre, what you say?
>> Yeah, let's go to that Luke 2 and uh
we'll read verses 34 and 35.
Go ahead, brother, when you get it.
>> And Simeon blessed them and said unto
Mary his mother, "Behold, this child is
set for the fall and rising again of
many in Israel,
>> and for a sign which shall be spoken
against, a sword shall pierce through
thy own soul also, that the thoughts of
many hearts may be revealed."
>> Yeah. So says, "Yeah, a soul shall
pierce through thy own soul also." Let's
go over to uh Zechariah the 12th
chapter.
Zechariah 12 and we're going to read
verse 10.
When you get it, go ahead, brother.
And I will pour upon the house of David
and upon the inhabitants of Jerusalem
the spirit of grace and of
supplications.
They shall look upon me whom they have
pierced,
and they shall mourn for him as one
mournered for his only son,
and shall be in bitterness for him as
one that is in bitterness for his
firstborn.
>> Yeah. Um
Jesus was Mary's firstborn
and she mourned for her son. Now, let's
go over to
uh John 19 now. John 19
and we going to pick it up at verse 16
and we'll skip from there. John 19 and
16. Go ahead, brother.
>> Then deliver he him therefore unto them
to be crucified. And they took Jesus and
led him away.
>> Read verse 23.
And then the soldiers when they had
crucified Jesus took his garments and
made four parts to every soldier apart
and also his coat. Now the coat was
without seam woven from the top
throughout.
>> Okay. Now skip down to verse 25. Let's
see who was there.
Now there stood by the cross of Jesus
his mother and his mother's sister Mary
the wife of Cleophus and Mary
>> Magdalene.
[Music]
>> And when Jesus therefore saw his mother
and the disciples standing by whom he
loved, he said unto his mother,"Woman,
behold thy son."
>> Then said he to the disciples, "Behold
thy mother." And from that hour that
disciples took her into his own home
>> because she was in mourning for her son
in mourning for her firstborn.
Now that part about piercing,
let's go over to uh 1 Timothy
6 and we going to read one verse there.
1 Timothy 6 and we going to read verse
10.
1 Timothy 6 and10. Go ahead, brother.
For the love of money is the root of all
evil, which while some coveted after,
and they have ered from the faith, and
pierced themselves through with many
sorrows.
>> So they pierced themselves through with
many sorrows. But this piercing is not a
literal piercing.
It's a figure of speech. It's a
mourning. It's a sorrowful uh position
that Mary was in because she was
watching her son
go through a crucifixion.
>> Right.
>> That's all I got.
>> Yep.
Thank you for that, brother. And we hope
that answers your question as we move
on.
>> Moving on. be alert as what are the
rules for head covering for sisters at
IOG.
Uh one, can they wear seeth through or
net light covering? Two, can any of head
part be exposed? And three, can they
remove their head covering during the
feast?
>> Brother Julius, what about this
question?
Well, part let's go to 1 Corinthians the
11th chapter. This is a a a commandment
and there's a reason why the Lord
commands a woman to have her head
covered. So now, what is the um rule for
the head covering
of women at the G? We follow what the
book say. 1 Corinthians 11:10. Read
verse one. Start at verse one.
Be ye followers of me, even as I also am
of Christ.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Continue.
>> Now I praise you, brethren, that you
remember me in all things and keep the
ordinance as I deliver them to you.
>> Remember what I taught you, Paul is
saying. Go ahead.
>> But I would have you know that every
head of every man is Christ.
>> Read that again.
But I will have you know that the head
of every man is Christ.
>> Yes.
>> And the head of the woman is the man.
>> And the head of Christ is God.
>> Yes. Continue.
>> Every man praying or prophesying having
his head covered dishonor his head
>> because he's in the image and likeness
of God. And God is man's head. Got to
have it. You cannot have a head covering
on if you are a man praying or reading
the Bible at the Israel of God. Go
ahead.
>> But every woman that prayth or
prophesies
with her head uncovered dishonor of her
head.
>> Uh-huh.
>> For that is even all one as if she were
shaven. So now every woman in the Israel
of God when she's praying or
prophesying, read the Bible, having a
biblical discussion and a solemn
assembly must have her head covered.
Why? Verse because it's it's about
respect, humility, and protection. Verse
10.
>> For this cause of the woman to have
power on her head because of the angels,
>> them fallen angels. Why? Because Satan
deceived the woman in the garden, not
the man. She walked away from her head.
Now the other question, uh, can they
wear see-through or netlike coverings?
Netlike covering is not a head covering.
I worked at a hospital. I seen when
nurses go into the operating room or h
doctors go into the operating room, they
had co not neck coverings. they had uh a
covering design uh for the operation
room. Okay. So uh if it's if it's a net
then the head is exposed
>> and how much of the head you got to have
from the front to the back. That's
called your crown. That's your crown. So
now
a fishnet or a net covering is not a
proper head covering. Look up the images
of proper head coverings for women in
religious services and they have full
coverings over their head. Full their
head is fully covered. And uh can they
remove their head covering during the
feast? During the feast after solemn
assembly is over, the service is over,
you take your head covering off. That's
all I got. Anybody want to add?
>> All right. I hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next
question.
>> Moving on. Uh, Leaping Lamb says the
rising of the dead in 1 Thessalonians 4
13-17.
Is it pre-tribulation,
midtribulation, or post-tribulation?
>> All right, that's a
legitimate question there. the rising of
the dead and that 1 Thessalonians 4.
Let's go there, Tanzel.
1 Thessalonians 4.
And they want to know, is that going to
be is this rising going to be before the
tribulation? No. Is it going to be
during the tribulation? No. And what
about after the tribulation?
Indeed. Let's go and read 1
Thessalonians 4 and let's pick it up.
at that verse 13. Go ahead, brother.
>> But I would not have you to be ignorant,
brethren, concerning them which are
asleep.
>> Sorrow not, even as others which have no
hope.
For if we believe that Jesus died and
rose again, even so them also which
sleep in Jesus will God bring with him.
>> So Jesus going to bring the dead with
him at a set time. Go ahead.
>> But this we say unto you by the word of
the Lord, that we which are alive and
remain unto the coming of the Lord shall
not prevent them which are asleep.
>> Those that are alive are not going to
prevent those that have died. Go ahead.
>> For the Lord himself shall descend from
heaven with a shout,
with the voice of the archangel, and
with the trump of God. and the dead in
Christ shall rise first.
>> So we see when the Lord himself begins
his descend and from heaven with a shout
and with the voice of the archangel
which is and with the trump of God
that's seven trumpets. Go ahead. Then we
which are alive and remain shall be
caught up together with them in the
clouds to meet the Lord in the air. And
so shall we ever be with the Lord.
>> So once we meet the Lord in the air,
then he's coming right back down to this
earth to do business with it. But it's
going to be after the tribulation. And
let's confirm that. Matthew 24. Let's go
to Matthew 24.
Because the rising of the dead, they
ask, "Will it be before the tribulation,
during the tribulation, or after the
tribulation?" The key word is after.
That's when it'll be. And let's back it
up with the books. Matthew 24 and read
that verse 29 and 30 for me, brother.
Immediately after the tribulation of
those days shall the sun be darkened and
the moon shall not give her light and
the stars shall fall from heaven and the
powers of heaven shall be shaken.
>> So we see after the tribulation is when
everything is going to take place even
what we just read in first
Thessalonians. Read that next verse.
>> And then shall appear the sign of the
son of man in heaven. And then shall all
the tribes of the earth mourn and they
shall see the son of man coming in the
clouds of heaven with power and great
glory.
>> So when you asked about the dead there,
hey, the rising of the dead, it's going
to be immediately after the tribulation.
Not before, not during, but after. And
that's when the dead and those that have
made the cut will meet the Lord in the
air and come back down to this earth to
help him straighten it all out. And
that's all I got.
All right, I'm going to leave it right
there as we move on to our next
question.
>> Yes, moving on. And the time is 8:21.
Jalia says, "Someone told me that
salvation is here now. God knew that we
couldn't keep his law. Jesus died so we
only have to believe. I tried showing
her the truth. She got loud. I walked
away. Am I wrong?
>> So the Dre's question is in need of some
light.
>> No, you're you're not wrong. Uh, you
know, the the book tell you to shake
your shake the dust of your feet in
Matthew 10 and 14. That's the only thing
you should have did was shake off the
dust of your feet. But let's go see what
Jesus said. Let's go to Matthew 19.
Matthew 19. And we going to read verses
16 to 18. Matthew 19 16 to 18. Go ahead,
brother. And behold, one came and said
unto him, Good Master, what good thing
should I do that I may have eternal
life?
>> And he said unto him, Why callst thou me
good? There is none good but one, and
that is God. But if thou will enter into
life, keep the commandments.
>> Now, this is the one that they said died
for their sins.
But you not going to believe him?
Read that verse one more time, brother.
Verse seven, 17. Go ahead.
>> And he said unto him, why callst thou me
good? There is none good but one, and
that is God. But if thou will enter into
life, keep the commandments.
>> That is that simple. You don't need to
add much to that. But read the next
verse. Go ahead.
He said unto him, "Which?" And Jesus
said, "Thou shalt do no murder. Thou
shall not commit adultery. Thou shall
not steal. Thou shall not bear false
witness."
Go ahead.
>> Honor thy father and thy mother, and
thou shall love thy neighbor as thyself.
>> Now, this guy didn't do one thing, and
that was covet.
that was his problem.
And so you that is a part of the
commandments as well. But let's go to
one other place. Let's go to first Peter
1. First Peter 1.
First Peter, the first chapter. And we
going to read verse three. Read that
when you get it, brother.
Blessed be the God and father of our
Lord Jesus Christ,
which according to his abundant mercy
hath begotten us again unto a lively
hope.
>> So we got lively hope by the
resurrection of Jesus Christ. Go ahead.
>> By the resurrection of Jesus Christ from
the dead
>> to inheritance incorruptible and
undefiled
and that fadeth not away reserved in
heaven for you. That don't mean you
going to heaven to get it.
>> It is reserved there for you. Go ahead.
>> Who are kept by kept by the power of God
through faith unto salvation. Ready to
be revealed in the last time.
>> This is when that salvation is ready to
be revealed in the last time. Verse
seven, go ahead.
that the trials of your faith, being
much more precious than of gold that
perish, though it be tried with fire,
might be found unto praise and honor and
glory at the appearing of Jesus Christ.
>> At the appearing of Jesus Christ, the
trial of your faith. That is why in
Matthew we tell you, he that endures
until the end endure what trial.
the same shall be saved.
>> Right
>> now read verse nine and that'll be it.
>> Receiving the end of your faith, even
the salvations of your souls.
>> Notice it didn't say when you just
confess.
>> It says the end of your faith.
>> Right.
>> The salvation of your soul.
>> That's all I got.
>> Yes, sir. And like you said, brother.
>> Yeah.
>> I'm sorry, Dre. I'm looking at that
question and the person said that
somebody told them that God knew that we
couldn't keep uh his commandments. Then
why did he give it to us? God is not the
God type of God that set you up to fail,
>> right?
>> He put a choice. He put a choice. Keep
my commandments and live.
>> How is the Abraham them gonna get to the
kingdom and all the saints gonna get to
the kingdom? They had to keep something,
>> right?
Julius look re let's go to uh Revelation
22:14 15 that is it if if the Lord gave
you these commandments to keep and you
don't keep them this is where you going
to be
14 to 15 go ahead brother
>> blessed are they that do his commands
that they might have right to the tree
of life and may enter in through the
gates and to the city.
>> Mhm.
>> Or without our dogs and sorcerers and
mongers and murderers and
idolattors and whosoever loveth and
maketh a lie.
>> And who is it that sent his angel to say
this? Read the next verse.
>> I Jesus have sent my angel to testify
unto you these things in the churches. I
am the root and the offspring of David
and the bright morning star. Jesus sent
the angel to tell you this.
Don't believe if somebody tell you
something different than what Jesus said
here. That's all I got.
>> That's right, Dre. And let's read that
verse 19 in that book, too. Because if
you don't keep the commandments here or
you telling people that they don't have
to keep the commandments, you guilty of
verse 19. Go ahead.
If any man shall take away from the
words of the book of this prophecy, God
shall take away his part out of the book
of life and out of the holy city and
from the things which are written in
this book.
>> Yes, sir. Because like Julius said too,
if we couldn't keep it, it wouldn't be
written.
>> That's right, brother.
>> You know, and like you said earlier in
Matthew 24 and 13, those that endure to
the end, the same shall be saved. can't
be saved today if the end is not here.
>> Right?
>> Let me let me throw
two simple things on the table.
>> All right.
>> What what is sin?
>> Transgression of the law.
>> Go to first John 3 and verse 4. Read it.
>> Yes sir.
>> Whosoever committh sin, transgress also
the law. For sin is the transgression of
the law.
Now, I want you to go back to Hebrews 10
and read verse 26 and 27.
>> Yes, sir.
For if we sin willfully after that we
have received the knowledge of the
truth, there remade of no more sacrifice
for sins,
>> but a certain fearful looking forth
judgment and fiery indignation which
shall devour the adversaries.
>> Keep reading.
>> He that despise Moses law die without
mercy under two or three witnesses.
Of how much sore punishment suppose ye
shall he be though worthy who have tried
none for the son of God and have counted
the blood of the covenant wherewith he
was sanctified and an unholy thing and
have done despite unto the spirit of
grace.
>> Now so the whole thing is sin is the
transgression of the law and if you sin
willfully ain't no more sacrifice. In
other words Jesus going to die no more
for you. So all you have to do look for
is the lake of fire. That's what's going
to happen.
So there's a person that said this about
a friend. I even give you another thing
that Jesus said. You don't have to read
it. Don't cast your pearls before swine.
>> Because they will cher your pearls and
then they will turn and ren you. Though
you person you try to talk to according
to the scripture is a swine. That's all
I got to say.
>> All right, Julia, we hope that that
answered your question with those many
different verses to help shed some
light. Let's move on to our next
question.
>> Next question. Kim Noel asks, "In Romans
11 21, it says, "All Israel shall be
saved." Is this referring to physical
Israel or spiritual Israel or both?
>> Or both? Brother Jerome, what you got?
>> Let's go read it.
Romans 11
uh verse 26.
>> Romans 11 verse 26.
And so all Israel shall be saved as it
is written, "There shall come out of
Zion the deliverer, and shall turn away
ungodliness from Jacob."
Yeah. It ain't talking about all
physical Israel going to be saved.
First of all, they they got a problem
with the very name wherein is salvation,
and that name is Jesus. Not all of them,
but a lot of them do. That's why it say
a lot of them all it's can't be physical
all physical Israelites. Okay. So and
and they don't want to repent from it
either. Okay. So uh but it's talking
about spiritual Israel. And spiritual
Israel encompasses all nationalities,
Israelites included. Everyone that take
hold of that of the covenant
of God.
>> Even the new covenant in the blood of
Jesus. Everybody that take hold of that
covenant and become the seed of Abraham,
>> right?
>> You the ones that's going to be saved.
>> Okay.
>> So, let's go to uh Galatians the 3rd
chapter and we're going to read verse
26- 29.
Galatians chapter 3 verse 26- 29.
>> Go ahead.
For ye are all the children of God by
faith in Christ Jesus.
For as many of you as have been baptized
into Christ have put on Christ. There is
neither Jew nor Greek. There is neither
bond nor free. There is neither male nor
female. For ye are all one in Christ
Jesus. And if you be Christ, then are
you Abraham's seed and hes according to
the promise.
>> Yeah, that's it. Anybody want to add
something, they can't.
>> Yeah, man. Read that Isaiah 58.
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
>> Yep. Indeed. And with Peter and Peter
and Paul being the go-tos for the
Gentiles, that mean they got a shot,
too. All the nations who pick up like
you said, brother. All right.
>> Isaiah 56. I'm sorry. Isaiah
>> 56 1-6.
Yes, sir.
>> All right. So,
>> the Lord.
>> Oh, you want me to read it.
>> That's fine. That's fine if y'all want
to. Isaiah 56 verse one.
>> I didn't know if you were just saying it
or you wanted me to read it.
>> Uh yeah, go ahead. Read read a couple of
verses since you're there, brother. Go
ahead.
>> Uh where you want me to start at?
>> Verse one. Verse one.
>> Yeah, verse one.
>> Read it to the six.
Thus sayeth the Lord, keep ye judgment
and do justice, for my salvation is near
to come, and my righteousness to be
revealed. Blessed is the man that doeth
this, and the son of man that lay hold
on it, that keepeth the Sabbath from
polluting it, and keepeth his hands from
doing any evil. Neither let the son of
the stranger that hath joined himself to
the Lord, speak, saying, The low have
utterly separated me from his people.
Neither let the unit say, "Behold, I am
a dry tree. For thus sayeth the Lord
unto the unit that keep my Sabbath, and
choose the things that please me, and
take hold of my covenant, even unto them
what I give in my house, and within my
walls, a place, and a name better than
of sons and of daughters,
>> I will give them an everlasting name.
>> Come on.
>> And shall not be cut off. also the sons
of the stranger that join themselves to
the Lord to serve him and to love the
name of the Lord to be his servants
everyone that keepeth the Sabbath from
polluting it and take up hold of my
company.
>> Read that seven brother.
>> Yes, sir.
Even then would I bring to my holy
mountain and make them joyful in my
house of prayer. If their burnt
offerings and their sacrifices shall be
accepted upon my altar for my house
shall be called a house of prayer for
all
>> all people.
>> All right. Amen. So all people got a
shot at this everlasting life. Whosoever
will let them come. The door is wide
open.
>> All right. Thank you, brother.
>> Go ahead.
Let me give you a more direct answer.
They talking about Israel.
Let's go into Matthews the 8th chapter.
You got a centurion came up
and asked uh the Lord
to heal his servant
>> and when okay I'll be I'll be on over
there. Then he told the Lord, "Look, I
ain't worthy for you to come under my
roof,
>> right?
>> All you have to do is speak the word."
And it's and uh and it'll be
>> We're going we going to read verses 9
uh uh through 12 right quick. Read
quick. This is what the centurion told
Jesus. You know, you know, I ain't clean
enough for you to come under that roof.
All you got to do is just speak the
word. Go ahead and read it.
>> I am a man under authority having
soldiers under me. And I say to this
man, go and he goeth, and to another
come, and he cometh. And to my servant,
do this, and he do it. But when Jesus
heard, he marveled and said to them that
follow. But verily I say unto you, I
have not found so great faith. No, not
in Israel. See,
>> so this man was a was a a Roman. He was
a Gentile. And he said, "Look, this man,
all he" He said, "All I got to do is
just speak the word and I know he going
to be healed." And then Jesus said, "I
have not found so great faith. Know not
in Israel." Ain't this what it said?
>> What it say?
>> Read the next read. Go ahead.
And I say unto you that many shall come
from the east and west and shall sit
down with Abraham and Isaac and Jacob in
the kingdom of heaven.
>> But the children of the kingdom shall be
cast out into out of darkness and there
shall be weeping and nashing of teeth.
>> Now do that say that all Israel going to
be saved physically? Mm.
>> The answer is all Israel is all
spiritual Israel is going to be saved.
>> Yeah,
>> that's all I have to say.
>> All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on, Sister Deborah,
with that time check.
>> Yes, the time is 8:38.
Detroit Price asked for you to break
down 1 Corinians 6 verse 16. What is the
difference in between being married and
joined as one flesh?
>> All right, brother Tanzil, we going to
pick it a little bit. Pick it up a
little bit as this time is a ticking. 1
Corinthians 6 and verse 16. pick it up
there and then the guest caller will um
take it from there about the difference
between being married and joined as one
flesh.
What know ye not that he which is joined
to a harlot is one body? For two said he
shall be one flesh.
>> But the whole thing is marriage ain't
got nothing to do with sex. Let me show
you that first. Okay,
>> let's go and read let let's go into uh
uh Genesis the 2 chapter and read verse
21 to 25
and the Lord caused a deep sleep to fall
upon Adam and slept and he took one of
his ribs and closed up the flesh instead
thereof
and the rib which the Lord Lord God had
taken from man, made he a woman, and
brought her unto the man. And Adam said,
"This is now bone of my bones and flesh
of my flesh. She shall be called woman
because she was taken out of man.
Therefore shall a man leave his father
and his mother and shall cleave unto his
wife, and there should be one flesh."
>> Now, Eve was Adam's wife, and they
didn't even know what sex was,
>> right? until third chapter of Genesis
where Satan told them about it. That's
why they got shamed through now. They
was one
spiritually here but they and and but he
called him a wife but he hadn't even had
sex. But let's look at Jesus. Let's go
into Matthew the first chapter read 18-
20 and we going to skip.
Matthew 1 18-20.
Okay.
Now the birth of Jesus Christ was on
this wise when as his mother Mary was
expoused to Joseph before they came
together which he was found with child
of the Holy Ghost. Then Joseph her
husband being a just man and not willing
to make her a public example was minded
to put her away privately. But while he
thought of these things, behold, the
angel of the Lord appeared unto him in a
dream, saying, Joseph, thou son of
David, fear not to take unto thee Mary
thy wife, for that which is conceived in
her is of the Holy Ghost.
>> Now, what did he call her?
>> Wife.
>> Now, skip down and read verse 24 and 25.
Then Joseph being raised from sleep did
as the angel of the Lord had bitten him
and took unto him his wife and knew her
not till she had brought forth her
firstborn son and he called his name
Jesus.
>> So that's Mary. It was Mary had nothing
to do with sex. So what is Mary? Malachi
2 and read verse 13 and 14.
Malachi 23
and 14.
>> And this have ye done again, covering
the altar of the Lord with tears and
weeping, and with crying out, in so much
that he regardeth not the offering
anymore, or receive it with good will at
your hand. But yet,
>> who is who? Let ye say, "Wherefore,
because the Lord have been witness
between thee and the wife of thy youth,
against whom thou hast dealt
treacherously,
yet is she thy companion and the wife of
thy covenant."
>> Now, that's the wife when uh uh uh uh
ain't got nothing to do with sex, but he
says the wife of thy covenant. That mean
that you have entered into some kind of
covenant, right,
>> for her to be
But now if you don't have I'm talking
and most covenants have
written documents.
Let's go to Deuteronomy the 24th chapter
and we're going to read the uh uh uh
verse 20 verse one.
Verse one. Go ahead.
When a man have taken a wife and married
her, and it come to pass that she find
no favor in his eyes, because he have
found some uncleanness in her, then let
him write her a bill of divorcement and
give it in her hand and send her out of
his house.
>> Oh, so a bill of divorcement for you to
have to give her a document showing the
divorce. Then you should have a document
showing that you got married. Isn't that
correct?
>> That's right.
got nothing to do with sex. But the
whole thing is so now if you going to go
with harlot then the Lord had Paul right
up here. Let's go into Romans 7 1 and 2.
Read
>> verses one and two.
>> Know ye not, brethren, for I speak to
them that knoweth the law, how that the
law have dominion over a man as long as
he liveth.
>> For the woman which have an husband is
bound by the law to her husband, so long
as he liveth. But if the husband be
dead, she is loosed from the law of her
husband.
>> I said Romans 7 1 and two.
>> Yes.
>> Maybe uh
right there said one can't uh uh uh
that's Romans 1 and two. But you know if
you're fornicating
Oh,
>> you want uh 1 Corinthians 7.
Did I say the seventh chapter?
>> Did you want first Corinthians 7?
>> First,
>> you want to deal with that. It's better
to marry than the burn.
>> Yeah, first I'm sorry, my fault. 1
Corinthians 7.
>> One and two and look at and then we
going to find uh better to marry than to
burn.
>> That's verse n.
Now concerning the things whereof ye
wrote unto me, it is good for a man not
to touch a woman, but nevertheless to
avoid fornication,
let let every man have his own wife, and
let every woman have her own husband.
>> So now when you become one with a
harlot, uh any woman, and you not uh uh
in a marriage, contracted marriage, you
are a fornicator,
>> right? And uh can somebody grab that
right quick and throw it in? Where is
the reading where it says better to
marry than to burn?
>> That's verse 9.
>> In that same chapter, verse 9.
>> Okay, read it.
>> But if they cannot contain,
let them marry for it is better to marry
than to burn.
So you can come become one with a wife
of your covenant and get eternal life.
But you become one with a harlot and
sleeping around you are fornicator
and you going to end up in the lake of
fire.
>> Simple as that. It's all I have to say.
>> Yeah. You don't want none of that. All
right. Hope that answered your question.
Next question. Deborah's time is a
ticking.
Next question. Brit Brett says, "A
friend of mine said, getting married
doesn't have to be on paper and a couple
can marry one another on their own." Are
there any scriptures to show them that
they what they have said isn't accurate?
>> All right, we gave you a couple. Guest
caller, what' you say?
>> The same one that we just gave.
>> Yeah.
Yep.
>> Okay.
>> All right.
>> You got Malachi
and then we got we got the seventh
chapter. 1 Corinthians 7th chapter.
>> They going there. They talking about he
going to marry. We going to make our own
vow. You sleeping around. First thing is
I want you to look at something.
The Lord had to in institute that
otherwise he wouldn't said give her a
written divorce. That mean somebody had
some papers on. Now say a man and a
woman get married and he have children
by this woman. But say he have a house
and he have a a bank account and money
in his name.
If he die,
this woman that he is not contractual
married to and his children that he had
by by this woman will not get nothing.
All of his uh uh uh uh things will go
unto
the closest relatives.
>> Yeah.
>> That's why the Lord told you, you know,
uh uh uh about this. Let's read
something here right quick. Let's read
Let's read First Peter 2 13-15.
>> First Peter 2
>> 13- 15.
>> Right. M
>> so submit yourself to every orders of
man for the Lord's sake whether it be to
the king as supreme or unto governors as
unto them that are sent by him for the
punishment of evildoers and for the
praise of them that do well. For so is
the will of God that with welloing ye
may put to silence the ignorance of
foolish men.
So tonight, he telling you to obey the
laws of the land. So you put to silence
the ignorance of man. First thing is
your wife and your children ain't going
to get nothing. Second thing is if you
decided to speak the word of God, ain't
nobody going to listen to you cuz they
going to say you shacking with somebody
and you a fornicator.
That's all I have to say.
>> All right.
If you don't have a proper documentation
or a certificate, your marriage is not
recognized by that state.
>> Right. And your wife and your children
will not get any of your assets if you
die.
>> Yeah. Yep. That's right. And they just
might sit you on the curb and you'll be
out of the equation all together.
>> Ain't no might. It will.
>> All right. We hope that answered your
question as we keep moving with this
time ticking. Deborah,
>> yes. She also asked for some
understanding on First Timothy 2 verse
15. Does this mean women having children
out of wedlock can still obtain
everlasting life? And she also gives
Psalms 127:E3
>> 1 Timothy 2:15 first Tenzel right quick
and then we're going to let Psalms 127
and3 but go ahead brother because does
this mean that women having children I
check wedlock can still obtain
everlasting life? Go ahead brother. But
notwithstanding, she shall be saved in
childbearing. And if they continue in
faith in charity and holiness with
soriety,
>> guess caller.
>> The first thing is what if she don't
have no child,
>> right?
>> That mean she ain't going to be saved.
>> No, I don't mean that.
>> Have nothing to do with salvation. Read
the next one. Then I and then we'll
we'll go we'll read some scripture. Go
ahead.
Psalm 127:3.
>> Lo, children are inheritance of the
Lord, and the fruit of the womb is his
reward.
So that's got nothing to do with a woman
having a child out of red lot. I'm going
to show you what it is if you going to
get salvation. Okay,
let's look at uh uh let's read
Ecclesiastes 9 and4 as far as salvation
is concerned. First Ecclesiastes 9 and4
but to him that is joined to all the
living there is hope for a living dog is
better than a dead lion.
>> That's him that's joined to the living.
I don't care what you've done. If you
had children out of wedlock, if you've
been a murderer, whatever, as long as
you living, you have the chance to get
salvation because you can repent. So
there is hope.
>> That is right.
>> Go and let's go into Matthew the 12th
chapter and read verse 31
and show you who don't have no hope. Go
ahead.
Wherefore I say unto you, all manner of
sin and blasphemy shall be forgiven unto
men, but the blasphemy against the Holy
Ghost shall not be forgiven unto men.
>> Now, all manner of sin might be forgiven
except for one, this blasphemy of the
Holy Ghost. That's somebody that know
the truth and deliberately teaching it
wrong. Go to Romans the first chapter.
over the first chapter and read 18 and
19. And we're going to skip to 28.
For the wrath of God is revealed from
heaven against all ungodliness and
unrighteousness of men who hold the
truth in unrighteousness.
Because that which may be known of God
is manifested in them. For God hath
showed it unto them.
>> So the wrath of God is revealed from
heaven against all those that have the
truth and unrighteousness. He know they
know. He's shown it to him. Even the
Godhead. So what he going to do with
them? Verse 28.
And even as they did not like to retain
God in their knowledge, God gave them
over to a repbate mind to do those
things which are not convenient.
>> Now when you get how do you get a
repbate mind? See God give it to you
that what? Let's go into uh um 2
Thessalonians the 2 chapter.
And we're going to read the uh let me
see where you going to talk about people
that love a lie.
Let's uh and
>> start verse nine.
>> Huh?
>> You want start at nine or you want to
get straight to it? Go. We'll start it
at nine and read down because this the
this man of sin that people going to
believe in it. Go ahead and read. So
even him whose coming is after the
working of Satan with all power and
signs and lying wonders and with all
deceivleness of unrighteousness in them
that perish because they receive not the
love of the truth that they might be
saved.
And for this cause God shall send them
strong delusion that they should believe
a lie and that they all might be damned
who believe not the truth but had
pleasure in unrighteousness.
>> So that's the so that is that is a sin
against the Holy Ghost. When you know
the truth and you teaching against it
and you won't receive it, he give you a
retrobate mind. What is what kind of
mind is that? That's a deceived mind by
God that you might be damned.
>> But as for somebody having a child, a a
child out of witlock or any other sin,
it can be forgiven except for anybody
that hold the truth and unrighteousness
teaches against it. God going to give
them a reprobate mind by making them
believe a lie that they might be damned.
That's all I got to say about that.
>> All right. Hope that answered your
question there as we move on to our next
question.
>> Uh, next one. Sky Ryder asks, and I'm
not knowing if I'm saying this correctly
or not, but he asks, "Is there a close
of probation before the seven plagues,
a time where is too late to repent?"
And Sky Ryder gives Matthew 24
37-39.
And he says, "Compare end times to the
days of Noah
and says also the ark close before the
rain." Genesis 7 verse 10- 16. I don't
know what uh the word that he's trying
to use or is this the correct word.
>> All right. I think uh brother Julius
will be able to pull some out of that
question and shed some light. Go ahead
brother.
>> Yes. I want to say first of all I heard
that like 15 20 years ago. That is a
popular Jehovah's Witness especially
7day Adventist teaching. There's a
program that comes on where this guy
talks about the close of probation.
That's where this question is coming
from. I saw the program and it's an
error. Number one. Number two, it says
that uh uh the seven plagues, the seven
last plagues is not the end of man. It
is prophecy being fulfilled. And number
three, let's go to the let's go to
Matthew the 24th chapter. No such thing
as closing uh probation.
And I'mma pick it back up what the guest
caller going to say. We're going to read
this right here and then we going to go
to to uh uh uh uh Ecclesiastes 9 and4
and then we going to give you an example
of that. Matthew 24 37-39.
Go ahead T. But as the days of Noah were
so shall also the coming of the Son of
Man be.
For as in the days that were before the
flood, they were eating and drinking,
marrying and giving in marriage, until
the day that Noah entered into the ark.
>> Go ahead.
>> And knew not until the flood came and
took them all away.
So shall also the coming of the son of
man be.
>> What is that scripture talking about in
the days of Noah? What was happening?
Read Genesis the sixth chapter on your
own. And let us go there. Let's look at
what was happened in the days of Noah
quickly. Genesis 6, we just go hit a
couple of verses.
This is why those people was no closed
probation. They had a chance. They was
wicked. The book says Noah and his wife
and his sons. No, they made it through
Noah's righteousness. Genesis 6 and1
when you get it. Go ahead. Uh Tenzel.
>> And it came to pass when men began to
multiply on the face of the earth and
daughters were born unto them. So you
can read the rest on your own, but I
want verse five. This is what was
happening in the days of Noah. And this
is what's happening as we proceed up all
the way up to the end. We are in the end
time now. And what you're seeing is what
you what you're seeing is all the signs
that was going on then. Verse five.
>> And God saw that the wicked of man was
great the earth.
>> But every imagination of the thoughts of
his heart was only evil continually.
>> And this is where we are today. Every
thoughts of man is wicked continually.
Have y'all noticed that uh it gets worse
and worse day by day. Times are getting
worse and worse year by year. So now
>> let's let's skip on down. Let's uh uh
let's go to one. What's the other
scripture they gave?
>> It was Genesis 7:10-16.
>> Yeah,
that was the days of Noah. But now let's
go to Ecclesiastes 9 and4. And I got one
more after this one. Ecclesiastes 9
and4. We going to kill it end of
probation. Uh probation. That's a
popular uh television program that comes
on. When you get Ecclesiastes 9 and4, go
ahead.
>> For to him that are joined to all the
living there is hope. For a living dog
is better than a dead lion.
for a living dog. It says, it says to
him that is joined to all the living
dead hope. Let me show you what a guy
did. Let's go to Luke the 23rd chapter.
Let me show you the hope that he got.
Luke 23. This is the thief on the cross.
The two thieves on the cross. One did
one acknowledge this transgression and
the other didn't. Let's look at the
question that he asked Jesus.
Two thieves on the cross. We going to
get right to the point. Look what this
man said at verse 41. Uh 40. Start at
verse 40. Go ahead.
>> But the other answer and rebuked him,
saying, "Do not thou fear God?"
>> Uhhuh.
>> Seeing thou art in the same
condemnation,
>> the condemnation of being crucified on
the cross for the wages of sin. Go
ahead.
>> And we indeed justly, but we receive the
due reward for our deeds.
>> That's acknowledging no transgression.
Go ahead. But this man hath done nothing
to miss.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And he said unto Jesus, Lord, remember
me when thou comest into thy kingdom.
>> He said, Lord, remember me. Pay
attention to what he's asking Jesus.
Remember me when you come into your
kingdom. Jesus didn't go to his kingdom
that day. He went to the grave for three
days and three nights. Continue. And
Jesus said unto him, "Verily I say unto
thee, today shall thou be with me in
paradise."
>> So Jesus didn't go to paradise. He said,
"When I come to my kingdom, you going to
be with me."
>> Right?
>> I want to pray. Now I'm looking for one
last scripture.
These are they that came out. Uh let's
go to Revelation the seventh chapter.
While there's life, there's hope. You
can repent like the guest call scholar
said and like the book say repent turn
from your iniquity so uh your sin so uh
iniquity won't be your ruin
>> while you got life you can repent
>> revelation
Revelation 7 read verse 9
after this I beheld in lo a great
multitude which no man could number
>> all nations and kindred and people and
tongues monks stood before the throne
and before the lamb clothed with white
robes and palms in their hand.
>> So now they got white robes which
represents their righteousness. Skip
down. Skip down and read verse
>> 13
>> 13. What's that?
>> 13.
>> Go ahead. Verse 13. Yeah.
>> And one of the elders answered, saying
unto me, but what are these which I read
in white robes? And when came
>> Uhhuh. I said unto him, "Sir, thou
knowest." And he say to me, "These are
they which came out of great tribulation
and have washed their robes and made
them white in the blood of the lamb."
>> So, so much blood for the seven plagues.
You got people that's going to go
through the great reh uh the great
tribulation period and they going to go
through these things and they going
because they going, it's going to try
them and their faith is going to deliver
them and they going to be given white
robes. Don't believe that myth about the
end of probation. That is television
drama. That's all I got. Cornell.
>> All right. Thank you for that, brother.
>> Yeah. The time is 900 uh 9:04, brother
Cornell.
>> 9:04. Okay. Well, we have ran out of
time and we want to thank everybody from
all around the world who sent in those
questions. We thank you and thank you
for joining us this evening. And we know
that there were some questions that we
didn't have a chance to get to, but
because we believe in quality more than
quantity, we ran out of time. But we
will address your question next week. So
don't resubmit it. Sister Deborah, take
your question and we will address it
next week. So until we all come together
again, we ask that you all be safe, be
blessed, stay prayed up, and may the
Lord have mercy on us all. As brother
Tanzel closes us out,
our Father, which are in heaven,
hallowed be thy name. Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done in earth as it is in
heaven. Give us this day our daily
bread. And forgive us of our debts as we
forgive our debtors. And lead us not
into temptation, but deliver us from
evil. For thine is the kingdom and the
power and the glory forever. In Jesus'
name we